[
    {
        "question": "Considering the types of settlement, the people of rural settlement are involved in different activities that does not include:",
        "options": [
            "Fishing and farming",
            "Mining",
            "Forestry",
            "Business and manufacturing"
        ],
        "answer":4 
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of soil does Sao Paulo region has which makes it ideal for growing coffee?",
        "options": [
            "Less fertile soil",
            "Rich soil",
            "Saline soil",
            "Unusable soil"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "Urbanization emerges out of rural settlement patterns when:",
        "options": [
            "Communities become self-contained.",
            "Houses become dispersed along main roads.",
            "The heights of buildings increase",
            "Trade develops between two or more settlements"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "A place where many people reside together is known as:",
        "options": [
            "Settlement",
            "City",
            "Country",
            "None of these"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "The rural areas of Brazil, such as the north-east Highlands suffer from extreme .............",
        "options": [
            "floods",
            "droughts",
            "inaccessibility",
            "accessibility"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "An organized pattern of human habitation is called a ...............",
        "options": [
            "Planned community",
            "Settlement",
            "Rural area",
            "City"
        ],
        "answer":4 
    },
    {
        "question": "Population is less in ............... river basin",
        "options": [
            "Ganga",
            "Nile",
            "Amazon",
            "Parana"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "Concentrated settlements are found in Narmada Valley because of its ...............",
        "options": [
            "Forested Land",
            "Cultivable Land",
            "Undulating topography",
            "Industries"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "How is the climate in the central part of Brazil?",
        "options": [
            "Unhealthy",
            "Healthy",
            "Cold",
            "Unpredictable"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "Of the following urban structures, which is the largest in areal extent.",
        "options": [
            "City",
            "Metropolitan area",
            "Town",
            "Urbanized area"
        ],
        "answer":4 
    },
    {
        "question": "The settlements that are found in the rural areas of north-east highlands of Brazil.",
        "options": [
            "Extremely dense",
            "Dense",
            "Sparse",
            "None of these"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "The least accessible locations within a city tend to be occupied by which land use?",
        "options": [
            "Commercial",
            "Industrial",
            "Residential",
            "Transportation"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "The place where individual lives is called",
        "options": [
            "Dwelling",
            "Settlement",
            "Both (1) and (2)",
            "None of these"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "Which State has the least urbanisation in Brazil?",
        "options": [
            "Para",
            "Amapa",
            "Espirito Santo",
            "Parana"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "The zones in which only one kind of activities are to be carried such as manufacturing are called.",
        "options": [
            "Business zones",
            "Catchment zones",
            "Economic zones",
            "Functional zones"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering the types of settlement, the people of urban settlement are involved in different activities that includes",
        "options": [
            "Business and manufacturing",
            "Fishing and farming",
            "Mining",
            "Forestry"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "Where do you find dispersed settlements in India?",
        "options": [
            "Near the rivers",
            "Near the transport routes",
            "Hilly areas",
            "Industrial regions"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "The settlements that are found on the Vindhyan Plateau.",
        "options": [
            "Scattered",
            "Nucleated",
            "Dispersed",
            "Linear"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "Dwellings are of ............... types:",
        "options": [
            "2",
            "3",
            "4"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "The growth of urbanisation in India has been ...............",
        "options": [
            "more",
            "slow",
            "medium",
            "doubled"
        ],
        "answer":4 
    },
    {
        "question": "The concentration of settlements is related to following major factor",
        "options": [
            "Proximity the to sea",
            "Plain region",
            "Availability of water",
            "Climate"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "Sao Paulo has extensive area under rich soil which makes it ideal for growing ...............",
        "options": [
            "tea",
            "coffee",
            "tobacco",
            "sugarcane"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "In settlement patterns, the settlements that occurs near rivers, coasts and railways are classified as:",
        "options": [
            "Linear settlement patterns",
            "Zonal settlement patterns",
            "Zonal settlement patterns",
            "Climatic settlement patterns"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "In North-eastern part of Brazil, which types of settlements are found?",
        "options": [
            "Nucleated",
            "Linear",
            "Dispersed",
            "Star-shaped"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    }
]